[
    {
        "questNo": "1",
        "question":
            "When a gas jar full of air is placed upside down on a gas jar full of bromine vapours, the red-brown vapours of bromine from the lower jar go upward into the jar containing air. In this experiment:",
        "option_A": "Air is heavier than bromine",
        "option_B": "Both air and bromine have the same density",
        "option_C": "Bromine is heavier than air",
        "option_D": "Bromine cannot be heavier than air because it is going upwards against gravity",
        "correctAns": "C",
        "submittedAns": "",
        "isMarked": false
      },
      {
        "questNo": "2",
        "question": " When water at 0°C freezes to form ice at the same temperature of 0°C, then it:",
        "option_A": "Absorbs some heat",
        "option_B": "Releases some heat",
        "option_C": "Neither absorbs nor releases heat",
        "option_D": "Absorbs exactly 3.34 x 105J/kg of heat",
        "correctAns": "B",
        "submittedAns": "",
        "isMarked": false
      },
      {
        "questNo": "3",
        "question": "The evaporation of a liquid can best be carried out in a:",
        "option_A": "Flask",
        "option_B": "China dish",
        "option_C": "T est tube",
        "option_D": "Beaker",
        "correctAns": "B",
        "submittedAns": "",
        "isMarked": false
      },
      {
        "questNo": "4",
        "question": "Zig-zag movement of the solute particle in a solution is known as",
        "option_A": "Linear motion",
        "option_B": "Circular motion",
        "option_C": "Brownian motion",
        "option_D": "Curved motion",
        "correctAns": "C",
        "submittedAns": "",
        "isMarked": false
      },
      {
        "questNo": "5",
        "question": "CO2 can be easily liquified and even solidified because",
        "option_A": "It has weak forces of attraction",
        "option_B": "It has comparatively more force of attraction than other gases",
        "option_C": "It has more intermolecular space",
        "option_D": "It is present in atmosphere.",
        "correctAns": "B",
        "submittedAns": "",
        "isMarked": false
      },
      {
        "questNo": "6",
        "question": " A few substances are arranged in the increasing order of ‘forces of attraction’ between their particles. Which one of the following represents a correct arrangement?",
        "option_A": "Water, air, wind",
        "option_B": "Air, sugar, oil",
        "option_C": "Oxygen, water, sugar",
        "option_D": "Salt, juice, air",
        "correctAns": "C",
        "submittedAns": "",
        "isMarked": false
      },
      {
        "questNo": "7",
        "question": "Which of the following phenomena always results in the cooling effect?",
        "option_A": "Condensation",
        "option_B": "Evaporation",
        "option_C": "Sublimation",
        "option_D": "None of these",
        "correctAns": "B",
        "submittedAns": "",
        "isMarked": false
      },
      {
        "questNo": "8",
        "question": "The colour of vapours formed on sublimation of iodine solid is:",
        "option_A": "Purple (violet)",
        "option_B": "Colourless",
        "option_C": "Yellow",
        "option_D": "Orange",
        "correctAns": "A",
        "submittedAns": "",
        "isMarked": false
      },
      {
        "questNo": "9",
        "question": "A gas which obeys the gas laws is known as:",
        "option_A": "An ideal gas",
        "option_B": "A heavier gas",
        "option_C": "A lighter gas",
        "option_D": "A real gas",
        "correctAns": "A",
        "submittedAns": "",
        "isMarked": false
      }
      ,
      {
        "questNo": "10",
        "question": "What’s the term used to describe the phase change as a liquid becomes a solid?",
        "option_A": "Evaporation",
        "option_B": "Condensation",
        "option_C": "Freezing",
        "option_D": "None of the above",
        "correctAns": "C",
        "submittedAns": "",
        "isMarked": false
      }
]